Muhammad Fathir Irhas

Software Engineer Jakarta Mobile/Whatsapp: +62-812-2444-1284Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/mfathirirhas

Email: fathir.irhas@outlook.com

Summary

Software Engineer in backend development well versed in Go Programming Language and other tools related. Experienced in microservices architecture. Fundamental with principles. Sometime opinionated. Always learning to improve skills. Able to work individually or in team. Trying to achieve solutions with best possible way and practices.

EDUCATION

• Universitas Telkom

Bandung, Indonesia

Sarjana Komputer (Bachelor in Computer Science)

2012 - 2016

EXPERIENCE

• Tiket.com

Jakarta

November 2020 - December 2021

Backend Engineer

• **Team**: Flight Prepurchase

- o Tech Stacks: Go, Java Spring, MongoDB, Redis, Kafka, RabbitMQ, etc.
- **Project**: Creating internal mock server for mocking part of inter-services communications, especially partner and integration with flight supplier.
- Working on flight search caching tools to populate search cache preemptively.

• Tokopedia Jakarta

Software Engineer

July 2018 - April 2020

- Tech Stacks: Golang, Javascript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, NSQ, gRPC, and GQL.
- Tokocash(discontinued): Create Whatsapp verification.
- Saldo Tokopedia: Designed and refactor deposit transaction identification. Saldo Tokopedia separation into Saldo Penghasilan and Saldo Refund. Frontend revamp and frontend APIs. Saldo Internal dashboard. Refactor codebase architecture to comply to some SOLID principles, saldo separation and for code coverage. Cron services.
- Internal Dashboard: Work on internal dashboard as backoffice to business and ops teams.
- **EGold**: Create datadog monitoring dashboard for Tokopedia Emas buy and sell success, attempts rate and collect error reporting in the dashboard.
- Legacy Code: Migrate some legacy code in Perl into Go.
- o Monitoring: Monitor services running through logs, grafana and datadog dashboard.
- Support: Support other teams to integrate. Support ops teams relating issues from customers.

• Anabatic Serpong, Tangerang

 $Software\ Engineer/Technical\ Consultant$

Nov 2016 - Jun 2018

- Tech Stacks: Java(Spring), PHP(Codeigniter), MySQL, Javascript.
- Emporia Digital Raya: Subsidiary of Anabatic. Worked on Eksporaja, a product as a channel partner with Alibaba for eksporter in Indonesia. Maintain Emporia main website. Worked on Udaily another product from emporia for apartment cluster management and daily stuffs.
- Anabatic: Worked on client site. Supporting development in Allianz.

SKILLS

- Domain and Specs: Backend Development, Web Services, Distributed Services, API, RPC, Message Queue, Persistence, Caching, Performance, Monitoring, Testing
- Main Skills: Go, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Cache, gRPC, GraphQL, HTTP, Message Queue, Docker, Testing
- Lesser Skills: Java, Javascript, HTML

LINKS

• Github: https://github.com/mfathirirhas

March 6, 2022